I picked up a couple of these Raphael
bars from the supermarket this morning.
I love this flavor. So, I'm going to
turn it into a delicious ice cream in
the Ninja Creamy Deluxe. And I'm going
to put a raspberry ganache swirl through
it. So, let's get on and make it.
This is the second time I'm making this
video cuz first time the camera decided
to be out of focus. I love Raphael. Love
Ferrero Rocher and all the variations
that they have. Not as much as I love
Lindor bowls. So, I thought it'd be nice
to turn it into a luxury ice cream. And
I made a raspberry ganache, a raspberry
white chocolate ganache in another video
on my other channel, which is this here.
So, make sure to head over there and
subscribe and do all the other stuff as
well. Um, and I thought they'd go really
well together. So, let's just get on and
make this. I'm going to make it as cold
processed as I can so that it freezes a
bit faster. So, what are we going to
need for the Raphael white chocolate ice
cream? You're going to need
190 g bar of Raphael chocolate, 387 g of
whole milk, 140 g of cream, 33% and up,
97 g of sugar, 11 g of corn syrup or
glucose syrup, 20 g of skim milk powder,
3 g of coconut extract, 1 g of salt. As
the Raphael has, this bar has coconut in
it. It's kind of, you know, encased in
coconut. I'm adding the coconut extract
to kind of boost that flavor. So, let's
get everything ready and get going.
First thing we're going to need to do is
put 200 g of our milk into a jug. And
into that, we're going to put in our
chocolate. Break this up. Into the
microwave. 30 second blast. It's going
to take a minute and a half to melt this
down. After 90 seconds or in three goes,
your chocolate will be soft enough just
to stir this together with this warm
milk cuz we want that to completely melt
into that liquid. There we go. We're
going to add in the rest of our milk.
187 g on top. Then into that, we're
having adding our 140 g of cream. We're
going to do our sugar independently
because we want to add stabilizer. 97 g
of sugar.
I'm going to use guar.
A few people have asked me how long this
lasts stabilizer. I mean, this is nearly
This is over 3 years old, this guar. It
is absolutely fine. So, we're going to
add about 75 g of our stabilizer in
there. Stir that together with your
sugar. In that goes into there. In goes
our skim milk powder, which is 20 g.
Stir that together. Again, the skim milk
powder will dissolve in that tiny bit of
residual heat. Skin milk powder will
dissolve at fridge temperatures in cold
milk. It absolutely does. It will just
take a little bit longer. It will take,
you know, half an hour to completely
dissolve, but it absolutely does. And
then in goes our coconut.
It's not extract, it's coconut
flavoring. So, this is a glycerin based
uh Frontier Co-op. I think it's from the
US. We're adding about 3 g into there.
Finally, a little
of salt. So, in this goes into our Ninja
Creamy tub. In the freezer, overnight. I
just realized I didn't put in the corn
syrup or glucose syrup. Today, I'm going
to use corn syrup because, you know, I
should have done this earlier.
Let's just
that together. There we go. Take two.
Back in the freezer again. This makes a
750 g 750ml batch for a ninja creamy
deluxe. If you want to make it in a
normal ninja creamy, then remove one/ird
of all the ingredients. If you want to
make a larger batch, then obviously just
scale it up to suit your needs. If you
don't want to make the raspberry white
chocolate ganache that's in this video,
then feel free not to. And you can use
fresh raspberries boiled down with some
sugar. I would thicken them up slightly
with a little bit of aar and some or
some guar. We're not going to do an
add-in setting for this because it will
decimate. And actually, in the first
time recording this video using the
add-in setting on a really thick ganache
just decimated it and just blended the
whole thing in with the ice cream base,
which is not what you want from an
addin. So, we're going to mix this one
in by hand to make sure we got some
really nice swirls. So, once this is
frozen, I'll come back and we'll get it
finished up. All right, take two on the
Raphael out the freezer.
Might help. Plugged it in.
ice cream setting.
Now, first time around when I did this,
I did the add in or mixing setting to
get this ganache in there as a swirl and
it just decimated the whole thing. It It
just mixed it in completely
and I didn't want that. I wanted, you
know, like a a ripple going through it.
So, I'm going to hand mix this one in
this time. If you don't want to make
this, like I said before, then you can
just use real raspberries. Add some
sugar, boil them down, add a bit of
stabilizer thickener, something like
that, like gua. Um, I wouldn't use corn
starch cuz that'll make it go kind of
semiopaque. So, you could use tapioca
starch to thicken as well, you know,
anything like that. Zantham. Uh, thicken
it up slightly so you can pipe it in.
And that's what I'm going to do now.
There we go. Raspberry ganache. That's
more like it. So, I'm going to swirl
this in myself.
That's better. That's what I was hoping
for.
Right.
Let's get some dished up. I really want
to lick that spoon. Is that bad me?
>> [music]
>> Much better
hand swirl. Let me take a picture so you
can see the difference. The one on the
left there is the original version which
didn't make it to film. And the one on
the right there is the hand swirled one.
You can see it's a very, very different.
And this is much more what I was after.
It's just a shame that the mixing
setting does that. Obviously, they won't
be, but Ninja and any company that makes
these kind of machines. Let me put these
back in the freezer. Slow your roll with
your mixing settings. The mixing paddle
speed should maybe one rotation a second
and it should only take about 3 seconds
to get down to the bottom of your
container. Then you've got a much better
distribution of your mixing. If you want
to go a bit further then add two mixing
settings. One for something harder like
cookies where you can actually break
them up a little bit and distribute them
through the ice cream. For like a
cookies and cream, then it doesn't
really matter and the spin speed can be
kind of like it is now. But for things
like liquids, ganaches, swirl, liquid
swirls, anything caramels, chocolates
like that, you want a much slower but
faster drop and rise speed so you it
doesn't just decimate it into the ice
cream. You want that swirl. So there we
go. Raphael ice cream
with a raspberry ganache swirl. Got said
that wrong. Raspberry ganache swirl.
That's what I was after.
That is delicious. That coconut kind of
touch, the flavor of that white
chocolate ice cream. So, yeah, white
chocolate, coconut with a a tiny little
bit of almond in there as well. That
coconut extract or flavoring boosting
that coconut flavor of that Raphael
chocolate. Delicious. And then that
raspberry swirl being a bit bitter, a
little bit chewy cuz it's a ganache.
That is perfect. Thanks very much for
watching. Don't forget to like and
subscribe. Haven't done a Ninja Creamy
video for a while, so I thought I'd do
this one. We're coming into December
soon, so I usually do some Christmas
themed videos. And then at the end of
the year, we'll do the catch up cuz
obviously this year has been quite big
for growth of this channel. And again, I
just couldn't be here without all the
support from my YouTube members and
Patreon supporters. Couldn't do this
without you guys. Thank you ever so much
and I'll see you next week.